brac.net 2015-06-12

# Privacy Policy | BRAC-Privacy Policy

**Respecting Your Privacy**

This Website is owned and operated by BRAC. We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us and how we treat that information. This Privacy Policy addresses those concerns. This policy may be changed or updated from time to time. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:

BRAC Centre  
75 Mohakhali,  
Dhaka-1212  
Bangladesh

Tel: + 880-2-9881265, 8824180-7.   
Ext: 3107, 3155, 3158, 3161  
Fax: +880-2-8823542  
E-mail: [info@brac.net](mailto:info@brac.net)

BRAC uses its best efforts to respect the privacy of its online visitors. At our site, we do not collect personally identifiable information from individuals unless they provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. This means we do not require you to register or provide information to us in order to view our site. BRAC only gathers personally identifiable data, such as names, addresses, zip/postal codes, e-mail addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by a visitor. For example, personally identifiable information may be collected in order for a visitor to make a donation online. This information is used solely by BRAC or other entities who are involved in the operation of this site for internal purposes. BRAC's lists are never sold to third parties. We will only share personally identifiable information with third parties when the person submitting the information authorizes us to share it or we are required to by law. As with most other Internet sites, our Web server automatically recognizes the domain name of each visitor to the site, but not the e-mail address (where possible). This IP address tells us which domain you visited from (e.g. aol.com). We use the information we record to help diagnose problems with our server and to improve the content of our Web page. The information is not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes.

**Use of Google Services**

In order to better serve our audience and expand our engagement outreach, BRAC has implemented Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting features. This enables us to improve online experience and better serve our web visitors. We will not facilitate the merging of personally-identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information previously collected or voluntarily submitted by the user unless we have robust notice of, and the user's prior affirmative (opt-in) consent to that merger.

 **Opt-Out**

Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics [using GA's current available opt-outs for the web](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

If you supply us with your postal address or e-mail address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on our programs and services.

If you do not want to receive postal mail or e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an e-mail to webmaster@brac.net or writing to us at the above address telling us that you do not want to receive postal mail or e-mail from us. Some mailings are prepared well in advance, so please allow up to three months for your request to be properly reflected on our mailing lists.

**Is Credit Card Information Secure?**

We care about the safety and security of your transaction. We use high grade encryption and the https security protocol to communicate with your browser software. This method is the industry standard security protocol, which makes it extremely difficult for anyone else to intercept the credit card information you send to us.

**How Do We Use "Cookies"?**

Visitors should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected by BRAC’s Website through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files a Website can use to recognize repeat visitors, facilitate the visitor’s ongoing access to and use of the site, and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements. Cookies are not programs that come onto a visitor’s system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the visitor that has no meaning outside the assigning site. If a visitor does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the visitor to deny or accept the cookie feature. BRAC uses "cookie" technology only to obtain non-personal information from its online visitors in order to improve visitors’ online experience and facilitate their visit within our site.

**External Links**

This site contains links to other sites. Unless we expressly state otherwise, BRAC makes no representations whatsoever concerning the content of those sites. The fact that BRAC has provided a link to a site is not an endorsement, authorization, sponsorship, or affiliation with respect to such site, its owners, or its providers. There are risks associated with using any information, software, or products found on the Internet, and BRAC cautions you to make sure that you understand these risks before retrieving, using, relying upon, or purchasing anything via the Internet.

**Note to Parents and Children**

BRAC welcomes children to learn more about our organization and about the issues presented on the BRAC sites, and we are particularly respectful of the privacy of our young users. We encourage parents to monitor their children's use of the Internet and to help us protect their privacy by instructing them never to provide personal information on this site or any other without permission. We will never attempt to extract unnecessary information from our users, regardless of age. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with such information without consent, we will use our best efforts to remove such information from our files. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that a child under 13 has provided such information to us, he or she should contact us at scott@bracusa.org.

**Updating Your Information**

We work to process and maintain accurately the information that you share with us. If you have donated to us and would like to correct or update your personal data or to adjust your mail preferences, you can do so by emailing us at scott@bracusa.org, calling us at 212-808-5615, or by sending us the update via postal mail sent to,

BRAC  
110 William Street, 29th Floor  
New York, NY 10038  
United States.

 **Photo Copyrights  
**

Photo copyright: BRAC/Shehzad Noorani/Jake Lyell/Saiful Huq Omi

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may, from time to time, make changes to our Privacy Policy, based on your comments and our need to reflect accurately our data collection and disclosure practices. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our website.

**Governing Law**

You agree that your use of this Privacy Policy and any disputes relating thereto shall be governed in all respects by the laws of the State of New York. Any dispute relating to this Privacy Policy shall be resolved solely in the state or federal courts located in Manhattan, New York.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on July 15, 2014. BRAC® and BRAC® and other marks used on this website are trademarks of BRAC or its affiliates and may not be used without permission.
